MATTHEW GALVIN

OVERVIEW

Proven technical lead with over ten years of experience in biotechnology and healthcare. I have a professional background in bioinformatics, data analysis, and software architecture with expertise in both product development and project management. My research interests include human health, equity, and philosophy.

EXPERIENCE

Dana-Farber Cancer Institute

Software Architect

Aug 2022 - Present

- · Engineering team lead for the MatchMiner project.
- · Python machine learning in support of precision oncology efforts.
- · ETL pipeline development and deployment.

Project Management, Airflow, Angular/React, Postgres, MongoDB

Invitae

Bioinformatics Pipeline Engineer

Jun 2021 - Jul 2022

- · Whole genome pipeline development.
- · Germline variant calling and data analysis.
- · Maintenance and on-call support for reproductive health pipelines.

HPC, Python, Singularity, Shell Scripting

Providence Health & Services

Bioinformatics Scientist

Nov 2020 - Jun 2021

- · Whole exome & T/N pipeline development.
- · Bulk/scRNA data processing & machine learning.
- · Analysis and curation of AACR Project GENIE data.

AWS, Docker, Python, R, Shell Scripting, Nextflow, IGV

Genomics Software Engineer

May 2019 - Nov 2020

- · Oncogenic pipeline development and data analysis.
- · Full stack web development.
- · Application owner and engineering mentor.

GCP, Ruby/Rails, Javascript/React, Python, Postgres, MongoDB

Illumina, Inc.

Engineer, Life Cycle Management

Nov 2017 - Apr 2018

- · Manufacturing software automation.
- · Vendor quality control and cost management.
- · Establish software best practices with manufacturing partners.

Project Management, Manufacturing, Python, Shell Scripting, SAP

Software Test Engineer

Sep 2014 - Nov 2017

- · Lead software test engineer for mid-throughput sequencers.
- · Engineering management and product planning.
- · Instrumentation software verification and validation.

Product Management, Genomics, Test Driven Design, JIRA, JAMA

EDUCATION

B.S. Chemical Engineering Oregon State University, 2014

LANGUAGES

Experienced in Python, R, Ruby, JavaScript, and Shell Scripting.

SKILLS

- · Software Architecture
- · Genomics & Bioinformatics
- · Pipeline Development
- · Machine Learning
- · Docker & Singularity
- · High performance computing (HPC)
- · Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- · Google Cloud Platform (GCP)
- · Full-stack Web Development
- · API & UI & DB Design
- · Material-UI & Bootstrap & jQuery
- · React & Angular
- · Flask & Ruby on Rails & Express
- · Data Visualization
- · D3 & ggplot & matplotlib
- · MSSQL & Snowflake
- · Postgres & Mongo
- · Process Automation
- · Software Verification & Validation
- · JIRA & JAMA & SAP
- · Agile & Scrum
- · Github & Bitbucket & GitLab
- · Project & Product Management
- · MacOS & Linux & Windows
- · Adobe Creative Suite
- · CITI Certification
- · LATEX

LINKS

- · matthewrgalvin.com
- · linkedin.com/in/matthewrgalvin
- · github.com/galvinma
- · orcid.org/0000-0003-2040-8567